[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient TOA automation
tutorial this is our lesson 32 in terms
of overall tricentis TOS automation
Concepts and this is our lesson 17 in
terms of lcen Tas advanced level
Concepts in this lesson you will learn
how can we use close programs and the
method task kill while automating your
test cases and while executing your tasa
scripts so I'm also going to talk about
standard modules called Start
program which comes along with with the
trient Tas so we are going to use this
Start program standard module to perform
close programs operation by using trient
TSA while automating your test cases
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you now let us jump onto
the system and see how can we perform
Clos program operation by using tricas
so this is my
presenta I've created one folder called
close
programs under this folder I have
created three different test cases okay
first test case is to close the
browser and the second test case is to
close the notepad program and third test
case is to close the tasar commander
itself okay so
now to close close any program there is
a standard module as I told you okay so
before we talk about using the standard
module close program let us first go to
Microsoft website and let us understand
what is this task kill okay so our task
kill is a method that is
used to kill your programs so in this
particular lesson we're going to use two
different arguments the first argument
is forward
slash IM specifies the image name of the
process to be
terminated so this argument specifies
the image name of the process to be
terminated and the other argument is for
slf specifies that processes be
forcefully ended so if I give this
argument that means forcefully end the
program which I specified okay so now
let us go back to trient
Taska so here first I would like to add
a test step to the Clos browser test
case for that right click and click on
ADD test
step and here I'm going to call the
module called Start program
and this Start program is coming from
standard
modules right and standard modules
process operations under standard
modules process operations okay select
this Start program and here so as you
all know or if you are aware of the
Start program standard module purpose is
to start the program but also the same
module can be used to kill the
programmer
so to start the program what we do we
generally specify the path of the
program let's assume it's a
[Music]
notepad let us say you want to close the
sorry you want to start the notepad
program so you're going to specify the
path of your
notepad from your system right that will
start the program but here we are
talking about killing the program so
that's why instead of specifying the
path of the program I'm going to specify
task kill argument I'm going to pass the
argument called task kill okay and then
in the argument I'm going to pass pass
my first argument
image why let me tell you so I'm passing
image because I'm going to kill the
program based on the image what do you
mean by that right click on go to your
taskbar bottom taskbar right click and
click on task
manager as soon as you click on task
manager it opens all the programs that
are running in your system all the
processes that are running your system
if you see in my system Google Chrome
Microsoft teams
notepad Taska Commander all these
programs are running so now I would like
to see the image name how can we do
that just right click on any one of the
processes and click on go to
detail and if you see it actually takes
you to the details you can see this is
your process ID and this is your process
name
you see Chrome has multiple
instances one program has multiple
process IDs right so now I need just
program name which is chrome.exe so let
us go back to here I want to insert the
program name as an argument
chrome.exe
and now I would like to pass another
argument kill the program forcefully
which is forward slash
F so now this test will kill the program
called
browser okay so now let us see how can
we kill the program called
Notepad for that again right click click
on ADD
tester and same way I'm going to call
Start Program from standard modules
right which is from process
operations and this time again in the
path I'm going to specify toask
kill right and
then here under arguments I'm going to
pass
forcefully kill the program and then
here I would like to close the notepad++
notepad Plus+ is open already so let's
again go to right click in the task
manager click on task
manager and then see the process notepad
is running in my system so now you need
to right click on
the program or process and click on go
to
detail and here you will find the
program name what is the program name
notepad++ do exe so I'm going to specify
the program name
here
notepad++ do
exe and now I'm going to specify another
argument forward sorry the main image
right this is actually I'm killing the
image
notepad++ do exe I'm specifying the
image as well right and now let
us run the test cases whatever we
automated till okay first I would like
to run the test case close
browser so if you see here bottom I see
one two three different tabs and also I
have a separate
window Chrome browser okay so now let us
just run the test
case right click and run close browser
so if you just observe at the bottom
it's going to close all the Chrome
browsers see it killed all your Chrome
browsers now you don't see any Chrome
browsers here right so started argument
and it killed everything so now let me
run another test case close
notepad notepad++ so this is your
notepad so I'm going to right click and
then click on run in scratchbook so if
you see this notepad++ should be closed
now yes so now you can see the notepad++
I think it's not closed I understand the
reason is see you need to specify the
image here okay let us specify the image
and then you need to specify the
notepad++
dotexe okay so I specified the notepad++
dotexe
then now let us run your test case so
let me run the test case right click
notepad++ do exe right click and then
run your command run your test
case so now
you you can see now your notepad++ has
been
closed
okay so what we did is actually the
arguments right the sequence of
arguments should be you need to
specify image and then your program that
you would like to close Okay that's the
sequence okay so this is done now let us
assume I would like to run these test
cases I mean whatever the test cases I
automated by using TR Tas by using batch
file let's assume for that you don't
need this tasa Commander if you would
like to run your tasa scripts by using
shell script or by using batch file then
you don't need Tasco Commander itself so
for that you need to close your Tasco
Commander also right so let's just right
click and add your
step and here again call the module
called Start Program from your standard
module okay and here let me first
specify again task
kill and then in the
argument for slim that is image and here
let us go to our task manager right
click on the taskar click on task
manager and here let us take the program
name of your tasar commander so if you
see my tasar commander is running so
right click and click on go to details
or so you can see my Tasco Commander
program these many instances going on
agent is running console is running so I
want tasar Commander to be killed right
click on Tasco Commander click on go to
detail and here what is the name of your
program the name of program is TSA
commander. exe tsco commander. ex let's
scroll down here see tasar commander.
exe so I'm going to specify Tsar
commander.
exe
tosa
commander.
exe okay and another argument is for
slash F for close the program so now
because this toas Commander will be
closed I'm going to save the task
whatever we did so now when I run this
particular test case it closes your task
of Commander itself okay let's run the
test case okay right click and
run your Tasco Commander will be
closed done it's closed your Tasco
Commander Clos let's go to your windows
okay so if you see your Tasco Commander
is no more visible right so this is how
you can use close program by using tbox
Start program
module so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your
queries hope you all understand the
concept of close program
and how can we use task kill by using
tricentis tasa while automating your
test cases or while executing your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
you